(this["webpackJsonpciv-svc-quiz-reviewer"]=this["webpackJsonpciv-svc-quiz-reviewer"]||[]).push([[0],{16:function(e,a,i){},17:function(e,a,i){"use strict";i.r(a);var t=i(0),n=i.n(t),o=i(7),s=i.n(o);i(6),i(16);function r(e){return n.a.createElement("div",{className:"setup-section"},n.a.createElement("div",{className:"setup-quiz"},n.a.createElement("h1",null,"Select Categories"),n.a.createElement("label",{htmlFor:"numericalType"},n.a.createElement("input",{id:"numericalType",name:"numericalType",type:"checkbox",checked:e.data.numericalType,onChange:e.handleChange}),"Numerical Ability"),n.a.createElement("label",{htmlFor:"verbalType"},n.a.createElement("input",{id:"verbalType",name:"verbalType",type:"checkbox",checked:e.data.verbalType,onChange:e.handleChange}),"Verbal Ability"),n.a.createElement("label",null,n.a.createElement("input",{id:"clericalType",name:"clericalType",type:"checkbox",checked:e.data.clericalType,onChange:e.handleChange}),"Clerical Ability"),n.a.createElement("label",null,n.a.createElement("input",{id:"analyticalType",name:"analyticalType",type:"checkbox",checked:e.data.analyticalType,onChange:e.handleChange}),"Analytical Ability"),n.a.createElement("label",null,n.a.createElement("input",{id:"general",name:"general",type:"checkbox",checked:e.data.general,onChange:e.handleChange}),"General Information")),n.a.createElement("div",{className:"setup-quiz-type"},n.a.createElement("button",{className:"setup-quiz-start-button",onClick:e.handleStartReview},"Start"),n.a.createElement("input",{id:"numberOfItems",name:"numberOfItems",type:"range",max:100,min:0,step:10,value:e.data.numberOfItems,onChange:e.handleChange}),e.data.numberOfItems<10?n.a.createElement("p",null,"Review Mode"):n.a.createElement("p",null,"".concat(e.data.numberOfItems," items"))))}var l=i(2);var c=[{id:15001,question:"question a",image:"",answer:"answer",choices:["choice 1x","choice 2y","choice 3z","choice 4a"],guide:""},{id:15002,question:"question a",image:"",answer:"answer",choices:["choice 1x","choice 2y","choice 3z","choice 4a"],guide:""}];var h=[{id:14001,question:"This is a type of document issued by a seller to a buyer relating to a sale transaction and indicating the products, quantities and prices sold to the buyer.",image:"",answer:"Sales invoice",choices:["Check voucher","Purchase order","Delivery receipt","Transcript of Records"],guide:""},{id:14002,question:"Which of the following is not a usual document used in a sales company?",image:"",answer:"Form 137",choices:["Check voucher","Delivery receipt","Sales invoice","Purchase order"],guide:""},{id:14003,question:"One of the responsibilities of a clerical job is answering and tending phone calls. Which is the best way to answer a phone call in a company?",image:"",answer:"Answer the phone politely and give your department or company name.",choices:["Say \u201cHello,\u201d and wait for the caller to speak.","Run and get a pen and notebook then pick up the phone.","Get the phone and ask them if they have eaten already.","Wait for fellow employees to answer the phone."],guide:""},{id:14004,question:"An example of a hard copy document is:",image:"",answer:"Business letter in a paper ",choices:["PDF file letter","Company email message","A business letter saved in USB","The company chat message"],guide:""},{id:14005,question:"What does a CC means in an email message?",image:"",answer:"Copy furnished",choices:["Copy sent","Crowd control","Copy cat","Client copy"],guide:""},{id:14006,question:"Which computer program should you go if you want to email a company?",image:"",answer:"Outlook",choices:["Word","Excel","Access","Powerpoint"],guide:""},{id:14007,question:"This is a telephonic transmission of scanned documents of texts and images to a telephone number connected to a printer.",image:"",answer:"Fax Machine",choices:["Photocopying machine","Scanner","Typewriter","Inkjet Printer"],guide:""},{id:14008,question:"The chief financial officer is responsible for the financial matters and financial management of a corporation, she is also known as the _______.",image:"",answer:"Treasurer",choices:["Auditor","Secretary","Chief Executive Officer","Manager"],guide:""},{id:14009,question:"Which department of a company is responsible for cash register operations and payment processing?",image:"",answer:"Cashier",choices:["Chief Executive Officer","Billing","Accounting","Budget"],guide:""},{id:14010,question:"Your boss asked you to send her a soft copy of your latest r\xe9sum\xe9. An example of a soft copy is:",image:"",answer:"A copy saved in a computer and sent through email",choices:["A print out copy usually in a paper","Original copy written in a paper","A black and white copy sent in person","A copy from a Xerox machine"],guide:""}];var u=[{id:11001,question:"(2x1\xf72), (4\xf71x2), (6x1\xf72), _____",image:"",answer:"16",choices:["8","12","4","32"],guide:""},{id:11002,question:"(15-8+3), 8, (4\xf72x3), ____",image:"",answer:"4",choices:["6","3","8","2"],guide:""},{id:11003,question:"Simplify: 33 1/3 % of 48 + 12 1/2 % of 96 - 44 4/9 % of 27",image:"",answer:"16",choices:["12","18","14","48"],guide:""},{id:11004,question:"12 is 125% of what number?",image:"",answer:"9.6",choices:["7.6","8","9","8.6","10"],guide:""},{id:11005,question:"What percent of 16 is 40?",image:"",answer:"250%",choices:["2.5%","2500%","1/4","25%","40%"],guide:""},{id:11006,question:" 1 \xbc subtracted from its reciprocal is?",image:"",answer:"-9/20",choices:["-4/10","0.45","2.25","-1/5","9/20"],guide:""},{id:11007,question:"What is the ratio of \xbc to 3/5?",image:"",answer:"5 : 12",choices:["1 : 3","3 : 20","2 : 6","3 : 4","5 : 4"],guide:""},{id:11008,question:"What is the difference between \u221a150 and \u221a54?",image:"",answer:"2 \u221a6",choices:["3 \u221a6","16 \u221a6","\u221a96","4 \u221a6","6 \u221a2"],guide:""},{id:11009,question:"A race car travelled for 2 \xbd hours with an average speed of 132 5/8 km per hour. Find the total distance it covered.",image:"",answer:"331 9/16 km",choices:["264 5/16 km","332 10/16 km","330 5/16 km","135 1/8 km"],guide:""},{id:11010,question:"99^0 - (-2)^2 + (3^2) - (-4)^2 = ?",image:"",answer:"-28",choices:["-30","-10","-9","30","None of the above"],guide:""},{id:11011,question:" (100)^0 + (-4^2) - 2^2 = ?",image:"",answer:"-19",choices:["19","-21","13","21","None of the above"],guide:""},{id:11012,question:"A one fourth percent of a number is 25. What is the number?",image:"",answer:"10,000",choices:["100","1,000","1,000,000","100,000"],guide:""},{id:11013,question:" A mini grocery store has a sale of Php 6435, Php 6927, Php 6855, Php 7230 and Php 6562 for 5 consecutive months. How much sale must he have in the sixth month so that he gets an average sale of Php 6500?",image:"",answer:"Php 4991",choices:["Php 5001","Php 5991","Php 6001","Php 6991"],guide:""},{id:11014,question:"The mean median and mode of 9 numbers are equal. The numbers are 12, 22, 10, 15, 14, 11, 19, 17.\tWhat is the 9th number?",image:"",answer:"15",choices:["14","12","16","18","11"],guide:""},{id:11015,question:"The mean median and mode of 5 numbers are equal. The numbers are 29, 18, 24, 25.\tWhat is the 5th number?",image:"",answer:"24",choices:["26","28","29","18","25"],guide:""},{id:11016,question:"90 increased by what percent of itself gives 180?",image:"",answer:"100%",choices:["50%","90%","150%","200%","130%"],guide:""},{id:11017,question:"If 500 or 25% of graduating class are girls, how many are graduating?",image:"",answer:"2,000",choices:["4,000","3,000","5,000","20,000","10,000"],guide:""},{id:11018,question:"In a group of 8, 000 applicants for a civil service examination, 1600 failed to take the first part of the test. What percent of the total applicants took the first part of the test?",image:"",answer:"80%",choices:["20%","30%","40%","60%"],guide:""},{id:11019,question:"If twice the value of a certain number is increased by 8 the result is 40. What is the number?",image:"",answer:"16",choices:["8","18","24","none of the above","32"],guide:""},{id:11020,question:" Cassy's father was 38 years of age when she was born while her mother was 36 years old when her\tbrother four years younger to her was born. What is the difference between the ages of her parents?",image:"",answer:"6 years",choices:["2 years","4 years","10 years","8 years"],guide:""},{id:11021,question:"Number Series: 100%, 2, 15/5, 4, ____?",image:"",answer:"5",choices:["2","3","4","6"],guide:""},{id:11022,question:"Number Series: 1/6, 1/3, 1/2, 2/3, ____?",image:"",answer:"5/6",choices:["2/6","2/7","3/5","4/8"],guide:""},{id:11023,question:"Number Series: 250%, 50%, 100%, 20%, 40%, ____?",image:"",answer:"8%",choices:["12%","10%","5%","15%"],guide:""},{id:11024,question:"Number Series: 0.1, 30%, 1/2, 0.7, 90%, ____?",image:"",answer:"1 1/10",choices:["1","100%","7/9","1.4"],guide:""},{id:11025,question:"Number Series: 5, 6, 9, 15, ____, 40",image:"",answer:"25",choices:["21","27","24","33"],guide:""},{id:11026,question:"Number Series: 5,16,49,104,____",image:"",answer:"181",choices:["170","148","115","164"],guide:""},{id:11027,question:"Number Series: 225, 336, 447, ____, 669, 7710",image:"",answer:"558",choices:["114","991","449","338"],guide:""},{id:11028,question:"Number Series: 563,647,479,815,____",image:"",answer:"143",choices:["672","386","279","455"],guide:""},{id:11029,question:"Number Series: 3, 12, 27, 48,75, 108, ____",image:"",answer:"147",choices:["183","192","162","156"],guide:""},{id:11030,question:"Number Series: 0.5, 0.55, 0.65, 0.8,____",image:"",answer:"1",choices:["0.82","0.9","0.95","1.2"],guide:""},{id:11031,question:" 1/2 \xf7 1/4 = ___",image:"",answer:"More than 1",choices:["Less than 1","Equal to 1","Undefined","None of the above"],guide:""},{id:11032,question:"If Kardo is feeding his buddy 1/2 cup of dog food but uses 1/10 of a cup, how many scoop will he\tneed to feed his dog?",image:"",answer:"5 scoops",choices:["1/12th scoop","1/20th scoop","4 scoops","3 scoops"],guide:""},{id:11033,question:" If 1 \xd7 10 = 9, 2 \xd7 10 = 18, 3 \xd7 10 = 27, then what is 8 \xd7 10 = ?",image:"",answer:"72",choices:["36","76","78","52"],guide:""},{id:11034,question:"83 : 25 :: 92 : ___?",image:"",answer:"49",choices:["44","51","40","63"],guide:""},{id:11035,question:"72 : 18 :: 56 : ___?",image:"",answer:"22",choices:["24","28","20","16"],guide:""},{id:11036,question:"2 : 12 :: 8 : ___?",image:"",answer:"18",choices:["80","128","396","576"],guide:""},{id:11037,question:"12 : 72 : : 8 : ___?",image:"",answer:"32",choices:["0","42","36","38"],guide:""},{id:11038,question:" PEMDAS: 10\xf72x5-(12\xf73x4)+1 =__?",image:"",answer:"10",choices:["16","1","-1","23","None of the above"],guide:""},{id:11039,question:"Sum of all odd numbers between 60 to 120.",image:"",answer:"2700",choices:["3775","3050","4000","2400"],guide:""},{id:11040,question:"John walks everyday from his house to the police station. After walking at a rate of 2 meters/second\tfor 3 minutes, he looks at his watch and realizes that he has to run 4 meters/second for 1 minute so he won\u2019t be late. What is the distance from his house to the police station?",image:"",answer:"600m",choices:["10m","60m","105m","500m","400m"],guide:""},{id:11041,question:"Radicals: \u221a0.000025",image:"",answer:"0.005",choices:["0.5","0.05","0.00005","0.000005"],guide:""},{id:11042,question:"Number Series: 1/12, 1/6, 1/4, 1/3, ____",image:"",answer:"5/12",choices:["1","1/3","3/6","1/2","None of the above"],guide:""},{id:11043,question:"A chemist has 400 milliliters of a solution of 20% alcohol on hand, and he wants to mix it with enough pure alcohol to turn it into a 30% alcohol solution. How much pure alcohol will this require?",image:"",answer:"57",choices:["30","40","50","60","48"],guide:""},{id:11044,question:"What is the percentage decrease from 80 to 60?",image:"",answer:"25%",choices:["33.33%","45%","20%","75%","None of the above"],guide:""},{id:11045,question:"What is the percentage increase from 60 to 80?",image:"",answer:"33.33%",choices:["50%","25%","20%","75%","None of the above"],guide:""},{id:11046,question:"A businessman sells 60% English books and still has 28 English books. Originally, he had:",image:"",answer:"70",choices:["47","39","60","50","None of the above"],guide:""},{id:11047,question:"Twelve and one half percent of 200 is what number?",image:"",answer:"25",choices:["112","12","50","45","None of the above"],guide:""},{id:11048,question:"If the price of a book is first decreased by 25% and then increased by 20%, then the net change in the price will be :",image:"",answer:"10%",choices:["20%","30%","40%","50%","None of the above"],guide:""},{id:11049,question:"In a mixture 60 litres, the ratio of milk and water 2 : 1. If this ratio is to be 1 : 2, then the quantity of water to be further added is:",image:"",answer:"60L",choices:["20L","30L","40L","70L","None of the above"],guide:""},{id:11050,question:" Participants in a certain conference from Luzon, Visayas, and Mindanao are in the ratio of 4:3:2. If there are 120 participants from Luzon, how many participants are there in all?",image:"",answer:"270",choices:["360","150","240","420","None of the above"],guide:""}];var m=[{id:12001,question:"The following are examples of Palindrome, except.",image:"",answer:"same",choices:["level","deified","noon","murdrum"],guide:"a palindrome is a word, phrase, number or sequence of words that reads the same backward as forward"},{id:12002,question:'That perfume always "evokes" pleasant memories.',image:"",answer:"calls up",choices:["angers","erases","restricts","confuses"],guide:""},{id:12003,question:'The attorney wanted to "expedite" the process because her client was becoming impatient.',image:"",answer:"accelerate",choices:["stop","evaluate","reverse","justify"],guide:""},{id:12004,question:'The suspect gave a "plausible" explanation for his presence at the scene, so the police decided to look elsewhere for the perpetrator of the crime.',image:"",answer:"credible",choices:["unbelievable","careless","insufficient","apologetic"],guide:""},{id:12005,question:'He based his conclusion on what he "inferred" from the evidence, not on what he actually observed.',image:"",answer:"surmised",choices:["predicted","imagined","expected","implied"],guide:""},{id:12006,question:"Sila ay nagdadamayan sa hirap at ginhawa. Sila ay totoong \u201cnaghihiramang suklay\u201d",image:"",answer:"magkaibigan",choices:["mag asawa","magkapatid","magkaaway","magkaanak"],guide:""},{id:12007,question:"There is no PANACEA that will solve our financial difficulty.",image:"",answer:"cure-all",choices:["problem","answer","paradox","criteria"],guide:""},{id:12008,question:"A multifarious task would ____",image:"",answer:"have many different components",choices:["have simple components.","have very few components.","be very complex.","be impossible to complete."],guide:" Multifarious means having many different aspects or components."},{id:12009,question:"Plaintive cries would be ____",image:"",answer:"sorrowful, mournful.",choices:["musical, soothing.","plain, uninteresting.","loud, jarring.","joyful, happy."],guide:"Plaintive means expressing sorrow; mournful, melancholy"},{id:120100,question:"People with inveterate beliefs ____",image:"",answer:"hold their beliefs deeply and passionately.",choices:["can be easily manipulated.","have adopted their beliefs from another.","respect other's beliefs.","change their beliefs frequently."],guide:"Inveterate beliefs are deep-rooted or firmly established."},{id:120111,question:"If you were involved in an altercation, you ____",image:"",answer:"had a heated argument.",choices:["had an accident.","had an agreement.","served in a war.","were part of a conspiracy."],guide:"An altercation is a heated dispute or quarrel"},{id:120122,question:"If you are a contentious person, you ____",image:"",answer:"are very competitive and quarrelsome.",choices:["are usually right.",'believe in "an eye for an eye."',"always try to keep the peace.","are secretive."],guide:"A contentious person is quarrelsome, competitive, quick to fight. Contentious also means controversial, causing contention"},{id:120133,question:"If you are part of a cabal, you ____",image:"",answer:"are involved in a secret plot.",choices:["are a against the minorities.","are participating in a protest.","belong to the majority.","are figthing against the enemy."],guide:"A cabal is a scheme or conspiracy; a small group joined in a secret plot"},{id:120144,question:"If you are a bellicose leader, you ____",image:"",answer:"are eager to wage war.",choices:["do everything in your power to avoid war","respect other leaders.","remain neutral during international conflicts.","treat all citizens equally"],guide:"A bellicose person is belligerent, quarrelsome; eager to wage war"},{id:120155,question:"If an apocalypse is near, you can expect ____",image:"",answer:"total devastation and destruction.",choices:["a period of extended peace.","a time of anarchy.","a grand celebration","an invasion."],guide:"An apocalypse is a cataclysmic event that brings total devastation or the end of the world."},{id:120166,question:"If your country suffers an incursion, your territory ____",image:"",answer:"has been invaded.",choices:["has been invaded.","is in a depression.","has seceded to form a new state.","has had a natural disaster."],guide:"An incursion is a raid or temporary invasion of someone else\u2019s territory."},{id:120177,question:"If you meet your nemesis, you meet ____",image:"",answer:"the cause of your misfortunes.",choices:["the leader of your country.","your guardian angel.","your death.","the person who decides your fate."],guide:"A nemesis is a source of harm or ruin; the cause of one\u2019s misery or downfall, bane; agent of retribution or vengeance"},{id:120188,question:"If you pillage a village, you ____",image:"",answer:"ransack it and steal as much as you can.",choices:["set it on fire.","destroy it with bombs.","negotiate peace between warring tribes.","clean up the environment."],guide:"To pillage means to forcibly rob of goods; to plunder"},{id:120199,question:"If you are a placid person, you ____",image:"",answer:"are usually calm and peaceful.",choices:["are happy.","are always trying to pick a fight.","are disloyal.","are not to be trusted."],guide:"Placid means calm and peaceful; free from disturbance"},{id:120200,question:"If you plan a reprisal, you ____",image:"",answer:"plan to retaliate.",choices:["plan to surrender.","plan to fight.","hope to negotiate a cease-fire.","plan to desert the army."],guide:"A reprisal is an act of retaliation for an injury. It is also the practice of using political or military force without actually resorting to war"}];var d=[{id:13001,question:"The official motto used in 30th Southeast Asian Games is what?",image:"",answer:"We Win As One",choices:["We Care As One","We Play As One","We Will As One","We Work As One"],guide:""},{id:13002,question:"On August 16, 2018, the government announced at least ___ Philippine holidays for 2019 as declared by virtue of Proclamation No. 555, series of 2018.",image:"",answer:"18",choices:["16","19","15","14"],guide:""},{id:13003,question:"Which of the following statements best describes the relationship between global warming ozone depletion?",image:"",answer:"Ozone depletion contributes to global warming.",choices:["Global warming causes ozone depletion.","Ozone depletion and global warming have nothing to do with each other","Excessive build-up of carbon dioxide causes both global warming and ozone depletion.","Ozone depletion contributes to build-up of carbon dioxide"],guide:""},{id:13004,question:"It is only Philippine province with an English name.",image:"",answer:"Mountain Province",choices:["Cebu","General Santos","Zambales","Nueva Vizcaya"],guide:""},{id:13005,question:"What form of government does the Philippines adopt?",image:"",answer:"Both Republican and Democratic",choices:["Republican","Democratic","Oligarchy","None of the choices"],guide:""},{id:13006,question:" Who among the following may issue a warrant of arrest or a search warrant?",image:"",answer:"A judge",choices:["A senator","A congressman","The cashier","The President"],guide:""},{id:13007,question:"A foreigner may acquire Filipino citizenship through",image:"",answer:"Naturalization",choices:["Extradition","Rebirth","Fixer","Visa application"],guide:""},{id:13008,question:'What is regarded by the State as a "primary social economic force?"',image:"",answer:"labor",choices:["education","trade","luxuries","commerce"],guide:'Under State Policies, the State "affirms labor as a primary social economic force." (Article II, Section 18)'},{id:13009,question:"According to Article III, Section 15 of the Constitution, the writ of habeas corpus may be suspended in times of rebellion or what?",image:"",answer:"invasion",choices:["martial law","war","terrorism","crime"],guide:'The writ of habeas corpus prevents persons from\tbeing arrested without warrants of arrest. The Constitution\tspecifies the conditions wherein the writ shall be suspended to prevent warrantless arrests, which were prevalent during the Marcos dictatorship (which was overthrown by the 1st People Power Revolution). The Constitution clearly states that "the writ of habeas corpus shall not be suspended except in cases of invasion or rebellion."'},{id:13010,question:"The Lower Chamber of the Congress of the Philippines is known by what name?",image:"",answer:"House of Representatives",choices:["Senate","Congressional Lower Chamber","National Assembly","Barangay Officials"],guide:'Article VI, Section 1 states, "The legislative power shall be vested in the Congress of the Philippines which shall consist of a Senate and a House of Representatives...". The Upper House of Congress is the Senate while the Lower House\tis the House of Representatives. Representatives are elected by the constituents in their respective legislative districts, while Senators are elected at the national level.'},{id:13011,question:"A Member of either house of Congress may be expelled by their fellow Members. For a Member to be expelled, how much of the total number of Members of a house must concur with the expulsion?",image:"",answer:"two-thirds",choices:["one half","majority","three-fourths","nine-tenths"],guide:'Article VI, Section 16.3 states, "Each House may determine the rules of its proceedings, punish its Members for disorderly behavior, and, with the concurrence of twothirds of all its Members, suspend or expel a Member." So, if the Senate wants to expel a member, 16 of the 24 Senators must agree to expel that Senator.'},{id:13012,question:"If a President wishes to veto a bill, he/she must communicate it within a certain span of time, otherwise the bill will become a law. How long is this span of time?",image:"",answer:"30 days",choices:["3 weeks","48 days","60 days","90 days"],guide:'According to Article VI, Section 27.1, "The President shall communicate his veto of any bill to the House where it originated within thirty days after the date of receipt thereof, otherwise, it shall become a law as if he had signed it." A\tvetoed bill may still become a law if two-thirds of the members of the house where it originated votes to make it a law.'},{id:13013,question:"What project of the DENR that includes the protection of Industrial pollution of our Environment?",image:"",answer:"Solid Waste Management",choices:["Bantay Kalikasan","Bantay Ilog","Bantay Dagat","Ecological Watch"],guide:""},{id:13014,question:"What government agency thus the status of government employee in the free voluntary services belong?",image:"",answer:"Barangay",choices:["Secretary","Regional","Municipal","National"],guide:""},{id:13015,question:"Which is not a ground for Impeachment of the Pres., Vice-Pres., Ombudsman, and Senator?",image:"",answer:"Against the family if the child is scolded by the parents",choices:["Graft and corruption","Sexual harassment","Grave abuse of the authority","Other crimes"],guide:""}];function g(){const[,e]=n.a.useContext(w),[a,i]=n.a.useState(!1),[t,o]=n.a.useState({numericalType:!0,verbalType:!1,clericalType:!1,analyticalType:!1,general:!1,numberOfItems:0}),s=Object(l.o)();return n.a.createElement("div",null,n.a.createElement("div",{className:"home-section"},a?n.a.createElement(r,{data:t,handleChange:function(e){const{name:a,type:i,value:t,checked:n}=e.target;o(e=>({...e,[a]:"checkbox"===i?n:t}))},handleStartReview:function(){e(()=>{const e=[t.numericalType&&u,t.verbalType&&m,t.clericalType&&h,t.analyticalType&&c,t.general&&d].filter(Boolean).flat();return function(e){let a=e;for(let i=a.length-1;i>0;i--){const e=Math.floor(Math.random()*(i+1));[a[i],a[e]]=[a[e],a[i]]}}(e),e}),s("/review")}}):n.a.createElement(n.a.Fragment,null,n.a.createElement("div",{className:"home-title"},n.a.createElement("p",null,"My ",n.a.createElement("span",null,"CIVIL SERVICE")),"Exam Reviewer"),n.a.createElement("div",{className:"home-start-button",onClick:()=>i(()=>!a)},"Click Here"))),n.a.createElement("div",{className:"about-section"},n.a.createElement("div",{className:"about-container"},n.a.createElement("h1",null,"What is the Philippine Civil Service Exam"),n.a.createElement("p",null,"The civil service examination is the government\u2019s way of screening and selecting prospective civil servants in the country. The Civil Service Commission (CSC) creates and administers this exam to determine which applicants are fit for a government job."),n.a.createElement("h1",null,"Types of Civil Service Exams"),n.a.createElement("li",null,"Professional"),n.a.createElement("li",null,"Sub-Professional"),n.a.createElement("p",null,"Passers of the exam for professional civil service level may be accepted for both clerical (first-level) and technical, executive, or managerial (second-level) positions in the government. On the other hand, passers of the exam for the sub-professional civil service level may be accepted only for first-level or clerical government positions."),n.a.createElement("h1",null,"Modes of Civil Service Exam"),n.a.createElement("p",null,"You can take the exam through the manual pen-and-paper test (PPT) or the computerized examination (COMEX). With the PPT, you take the test using a text booklet and an answer sheet. The COMEX, on the other hand, is conducted online."),n.a.createElement("h1",null,"Civil Service Examination Coverage"),n.a.createElement("p",null,"Civil service exams in the Philippines are similar to college entrance exams in scope. Given in English and Filipino, the examination covers the following subjects for both professional and sub-professional levels:"),n.a.createElement("h3",null,"General information"),n.a.createElement("li",null,"The Philippine Constitution "),n.a.createElement("li",null,"Code of Conduct and Ethical Standards for Public Officials and Employees (R.A. 6713)"),n.a.createElement("li",null,"Peace and Human Rights Issues and Concepts "),n.a.createElement("li",null,"Environment Management and Protection"),n.a.createElement("h3",null,"Numerical Ability"),n.a.createElement("li",null,"Basic operations"),n.a.createElement("li",null,"Word problems"),n.a.createElement("h3",null,"Verbal Ability"),n.a.createElement("li",null,"Grammar and correct usage"),n.a.createElement("li",null,"Vocabulary"),n.a.createElement("li",null,"Paragraph organization"),n.a.createElement("li",null,"Reading comprehension"),n.a.createElement("h3",null,"Clerical Ability (Sub-professional)"),n.a.createElement("li",null,"Filing"),n.a.createElement("li",null,"Spelling"),n.a.createElement("h3",null,"Analytical Ability (Professional)"),n.a.createElement("li",null,"Word association "),n.a.createElement("li",null,"Identifying assumptions and conclusions"),n.a.createElement("li",null,"Logic "),n.a.createElement("li",null,"Data interpretation "),n.a.createElement("h1",null,"Who Can Take the Civil Service Exam?"),n.a.createElement("p",null,"This test is open to anyone who meets the following civil service exam eligibility requirements:"),n.a.createElement("li",null,"Filipino citizen"),n.a.createElement("li",null,"At least 18 years old during the filing of the application"),n.a.createElement("li",null,"Of good moral character "),n.a.createElement("li",null,"No conviction of an offense or crime"),n.a.createElement("li",null,"No dismissal from military or government service"),n.a.createElement("li",null,"Has never taken the same level of civil service within three months before the examination date"),n.a.createElement("li",null,"A high school graduate or a college undergraduate can take the civil service exam."),n.a.createElement("h1",null,"Who is Exempted from Taking the Exam?"),n.a.createElement("p",null,"Not all Filipinos who want to work in the government must take the civil service exam. The CSC grants exemption to the following individuals who are already considered eligible for civil service:"),n.a.createElement("li",null,"Bar exam passers"),n.a.createElement("li",null,"Board exam passers"),n.a.createElement("li",null,"Honor graduates (summa cum laude, magna cum laude, or cum laude)"),n.a.createElement("li",null,"Barangay health workers"),n.a.createElement("li",null,"Barangay officials"),n.a.createElement("li",null,"Sanggunian members"),n.a.createElement("li",null,"Barangay nutrition scholars"),n.a.createElement("li",null,"Electronic Data Processing Specialist eligibles"),n.a.createElement("li",null,"Scientific and Technological Specialist eligibles "),n.a.createElement("li",null,"Veteran Preference Rating eligibles"),n.a.createElement("p",null,"Those who qualify for the exemption no longer need to take the civil service exam but must apply for a Certificate of Eligibility at a CSC Regional Office or Field Office."),n.a.createElement("h1",null,"The Exam"),n.a.createElement("li",null,"Professional-level examinees need to answer 170 items within 3 hours and 10 minutes"),n.a.createElement("li",null,"Sub-professional-level examinees have 2 hours and 40 minutes to answer a total of 165 items."),n.a.createElement("li",null,"Examinees should get a rating of at least 80 to pass. "),n.a.createElement("a",{href:"https://csc.gov.ph/phocadownload/userupload/erpo/announcements/2023/ExamAnnouncement05s2023_Conduct%20of%202024-0303%20CSE-PPT.pdf",target:"__blank"},"Read More"),n.a.createElement("h1",null,"Why this Website?"),n.a.createElement("li",null,"This simple project served as a learning activity for learning vanilla ReactJS."),n.a.createElement("h1",null,"Disclaimer"),n.a.createElement("li",null,"Insert comment."),n.a.createElement("h1",null,"Sources"),n.a.createElement("li",null,"------"))),n.a.createElement("footer",null))}function p(){const[e]=n.a.useContext(w),[a,i]=n.a.useState({question:"",answer:"",choices:["","","",""]}),[t,o]=n.a.useState("review"),[s,r]=n.a.useState(0),[c,h]=n.a.useState(0),[u,m]=n.a.useState(!1),[d,g]=n.a.useState(0),p=Object(l.o)(),f={border:"8px solid #eee",backgroundColor:"transparent"},y={border:"2px solid #444"},b={border:"8px solid #eee",backgroundColor:"transparent"};function v(a){const t=Math.floor(4*Math.random()),n=[...a];for(let e=n.length-1;e>0;e--){const a=Math.floor(Math.random()*(e+1));[n[e],n[a]]=[n[a],n[e]]}return n[t]=e[c].answer,i(()=>({question:e[c].question,answer:t,choices:n})),n}function E(i){u||(m(!0),g(i),i===a.answer&&r(e=>e+1),h(a=>a+1>=e.length?0:a+1))}return n.a.useEffect(()=>{e[c].choices?v(e[c].choices):p("/")},[]),n.a.createElement("div",{className:"flash-cards-container"},n.a.createElement("div",{className:"flash-card-score"},n.a.createElement("p",null,t),n.a.createElement("p",null,"score: ",s),n.a.createElement("p",null,"TIME: 00:00:00")),n.a.createElement("div",{className:"flash-card-main-content"},n.a.createElement("div",{className:"flash-card-question"},a.question),n.a.createElement("ul",{className:"choices"},a.choices.slice(0,4).map((e,i)=>u&&i===d&&i===a.answer?n.a.createElement("li",{key:i,onClick:()=>E(i),style:f},e):u&&i===d?n.a.createElement("li",{key:i,onClick:()=>E(i),style:y},e):u&&i===a.answer?n.a.createElement("li",{key:i,onClick:()=>E(i),style:b},e):n.a.createElement("li",{key:i,onClick:()=>E(i)},e)))),n.a.createElement("div",{className:"question-finished-box"},u&&n.a.createElement("div",{onClick:function(){m(!1),v(e[c].choices)},className:"question-finished-box-button"},"Next")))}var f=i(3);const w=n.a.createContext();var y=function(){const[e,a]=n.a.useState([{}]);return n.a.createElement(f.a,null,n.a.createElement(w.Provider,{value:[e,a]},n.a.createElement(l.c,null,n.a.createElement(l.a,{path:"/",element:n.a.createElement(g,null)}),n.a.createElement(l.a,{path:"/review",element:n.a.createElement(p,null)}))))};var b=e=>{e&&e instanceof Function&&i.e(3).then(i.bind(null,18)).then(a=>{let{getCLS:i,getFID:t,getFCP:n,getLCP:o,getTTFB:s}=a;i(e),t(e),n(e),o(e),s(e)})};s.a.createRoot(document.getElementById("root")).render(n.a.createElement(n.a.StrictMode,null,n.a.createElement(y,null))),b()},6:function(e,a,i){},8:function(e,a,i){e.exports=i(17)}},[[8,1,2]]]);
//# sourceMappingURL=main.ef52c4de.chunk.js.map